Break again folks...actually...the back someone wave hand thank you perfect.
...about three more minutes former,
former minutes here before we can start.
In the meantime maybe I can ask you guys like how you
...are doing a enjoying bill so far.
You guys check out...check out the whole length
...and the stuff poland's can do nobody.
I think it's here somewhere we're not allowed to go-there actually it's only for customers.
I mean I would love to play my...it but I just have analysis.
Yes, I mean I don't havethat doesn't mean like I mean I'm sure like there must be like
know very little about it was like a very hush-hushproject but it looks pretty cool.
So, this is a quick server you're like how many people actually today
...stuff using cplus-plus you guys all
...cplus-plus users perfect.
That's a good crash and how many of you guys are actually milling mobile apps?
How many of you guys...for platforms...windows?
...perfect so if that is the case you guys have come to
the right talk thank you for choosing us over some of the other...available at this time.
...one-minute...I can actually officially start.
Yes, everybody come here perfect more people coming in great.
...can actually
start so if you guys can settle...I'm actually going to get started here.
So, this talk is going to be about
...building cross-platform mobile apps using cplus-plus this is something new that we've
...twenty fifteen to introduce myself and I
...a I am a program manager I work in the visual...team.
And, this session essentially is going to be a bunch of
...like for a few slides essentially just give you guys an overview of...you know,
mobile platform technologies look lag where some
of the strategies and then we'll get into some doing some cool demos so I want
to session to be interactive so essentially please participate when
ask us questions because ...sessions is not only giving information to you guys
there's also getting information back for us so we can build a...for us.
So, evaluation yes so please said do
...evaluations here for each...session their important in-house the speakers
like myself improve and also helps us if...actually presented...content that's useful for
you guys as you go through the sessions so please take time to do that and the of
the session hopefully good and, with that I'll get started the first slide here so the first slide
here's about more platforms more opportunities...so if you take a look at
the current mobile user which I'm sure all you guys are we all have our favorite
set of applications and we want to be able to use them across a
wiesel devices I might have an android phone at work but I might have
...at home and I will be able to use the same app across these two platforms as
a result developers is you guys going to be able to target
mode platform because targeting...platforms for you guys means more
money or opportunity for someone like me if I'm...more...good famous.
So, if you go ahead and you want to designer application mobile application there's multiple ways you can
go about this the first approach you guys can take is essentially the
...approach which is basically you can go ahead go ahead and
build the application on each platform in the popular language on the platform that
would be like csharp on windows...see and...swifton ios.
Android and java.
So, on so obviously a lot of
...rhythms matter and there's benefits...approach now if...using this kind of
an approach where you guys can do is that you guys have the full native experience
you guys have access to the platform sdk which allows you to access all platform api
...an leverage the full feature compatibility on...platform.
...are also some negatives...this kind of an approach...you guys now that I server the start
...guys are cplus-plus users in fact how many people actually think that there
...some of the negatives you guys can think of...anybody in the room.
So, again, compiler compilers...compatible interesting and the of sir.
Bingo that's correct...correct you have to writer
...three times so the negatives here the first from being there is minimal call reuse
now imagine I'm actually creating a new feature on my application that's being targeting all
these platforms after...three times as...and cplus-plus or cx in windows
...sharpen windows when objective cfour ios java for android so on.
So, that's not good.
As result your no-win customer or...increases so on right so let's
...another trivia question here the question is for you guys again how many of
the top fifty applications in the android place for us leverage cc pascal.
So, the first choices men and people actually think that in the top fifty application the and replaced
...now them actually using cplus-plus.
Okay, how many people think that there's ten percent of the applications on the and replaced
...using cplus-plus?
Our people...forty percent applications that are using super-fast in the top fifty.
And, who's going...the brave one here and say that eighty percent of the applications on the and replace
...using cplus-plus how we have a smart bunch here.
So, the reason
...slide was because the answer is obviously eighty percent surprising how many people
find surprising that eighty percent of the and replace laptop application...and
...fifty or using cplus-plus well let's take a look at
these applications are so again this data is a...couple of weeks-old so don't
assuming if any of the order changed here so,
the platform defining apps like facebook.
Candy crush there's a couple of candy...folks
...the...said known the mention them but I'm going to mention anyways ...
another microsoft application temple run twitter
all these famous platform defining applications are currently using cplus-plus.
Now a lot now if you talk about, you know, in what quantity
their leveraging cplus-plus that's actually difference if you talk about an application like
scribe which is basically truly cross-platform mobile which targets android ios and,
windows they have about seventy to eighty percent of their code...in cplus-plus the same
is the case of office so the other apps like facebook might be using only
a small library or small portion of their functionality better leather leveraging
...using cplus-plus so the mileage varies...thing
that's for sure all this stuff fifty apps...something in common among them...using cplus-plus.
Now cplus-plus from a language perspective is supporter
all these platforms and if I actually go ahead and write my cross-platform
code let's say my business other government application in cplus-plus and actually have a
lightweight ui on top of that in the platform language then I can still actually get the
benefits that I want from a perspective a fully of experience I get the platform sdk
...access to it so I can actually access any of the api
is but there's also some other advantages the obvious one is we use.
Worse on
the other advantages you guys can think of maybe some from that side of the room is time.
...speed absolutely performance the
age-old argument of using cplus-plus over
languages is performance and that is absolutely correct cc
...code runs directly on the hardware as compared to traditional dot net or java
code also if you want to access the advance
...instructions or neon instructions on your great a...galaxy
as five device I guess what do you using cplus-plus if you want to have food animations
in your games...using cplus-plus.
Also if you take a look around most of the mobile platforms today
...arm chips arm is great for battery life but it's not-so-great when
compared to some of the into counterparts maybe for runtime performance maybe again
and over there if using seep...every allen's performance they again from
...on those to mobile devices is worth its weight in pounds and that is
exactly so the reasons why those apps that I mention there are using
...move on here these slides will be available for people just people thing pictures
so...actually...we've seen like, you know, what kind of apps using cplus-plus so on
let's look at how does the architecture look like so apps like office
scribe bing maps drop box?
I mean there's a great talk by drop box and using
...cross-platform retrace you look for it is hyperlink in the presentations well all these apps
are there have a very...layer of their code...cross-platform
...cplus-plus office...ninety percent of their code and cplus-plus.
And, then you basically go ahead and write your ui or
...layer...software in the lightweight language it could be xml java in case of android
...axis axes it using jan I, you know,
which is a job...interface into your...layer and the same you can do for windows using
p invoke or...objective see wrapper so on so this is a
...approach but it has challenges?
Now if I actually using.
If you're actually using cplus-plus across these different platform their challenges so far we've seen that,
you know, it's actually good I can actually, you know, right my cross-platform
conan cplus-plus and the ability to do that every platform you
...architecture now we talking about some of the challenges are there when you're trying to use cplus-plus
there is a variety of compilers someone earlier mention compilers
here you see a variety of comparison using platforms right there's a visual see
...for the windows platform is...and dc from the...there's triangle
...is the apples version of triangle vm there's different building...
There's different id easter's visual studio for windows...eclipse today...
development android needed development and which studio for java so on and there's...obviously for mac?
Which brings us to this slide which talks about some of the challenges that we have,
you know,...summarizes...the challenges...have
...cplus-plus now you guys in the room people using
cplus-plus I'm show you guys can locate yourself either
in a column or row and column so on so, the challenges
here all these tools installing them there's different acquisition experiences,
you know, you have to go figure out how to install if we talk about the and platform you got install
android and dk the sdk and java set of the right plug...clip so
you can debug the code so on there's chat there's definitely problems there...having multiple
installation experiences if that's not enough you guys have to go ahead and figure out how
these multiple tools?
You know, the flags between clang ans and the visual studio compiler the microsoft compiler
different there's compatibility issues the way the pcs works is different so on and of course there's
from both systems I mean, you know, as we learning about x code build
...is bill...to be honest yielding common them's...
So,...actually different
...system that you guys have to use today to debugging so one of the primary reasons you
know, you'll see like for experience...next slide is that debugging experience specially for the and
platforms not accurate especially the android...debugging experience those of you guys here in the room
...actually develop an application for android which uses cplus-plus how...people find
...debugging spurs numbing ideal what is actually a few people here people over there
every glasses...really see that far but I saw some answer.
Also another thing here multiple see...there's x code for ios there's
and there's android studio an eclipse for android...studio for windows
...you guys are used to trying out your favorite key bindings and shortcuts so
on the lighten level
...id that's actually hard to keep changing eighties so on.
So, with that said.
Starting with visual...twenty fifteen rc we want to share some
...guys right this is really exciting time for us from visual studio team we
Network ons animation last night starting...visual studio twelve-fifty rc
...start seeing.
The experience that we're trying to provide for cross-platform see buffers developers such as yourself here.
Using this experience you'll be able to easily install oggenc cross-platform
needs this means that you can actually install your first party microsoft software, you know,
the templates in the project in both system
that's so on you can also install your third-party suffer which includes you android
...android sdk and java so on not only that you can also
manage dependencies and, be able you'll be notified in notification managing set of bs
has new versions of them become available and you can absolutely update your bits as the need b.
There will be one single cplus-plus id evil offering that one-c
...id for all your cross-platform needs to currently we're focusing on that fat cplus-plus
...of software and we believe...twenty fifteen rc.
The idea of choice will programs for the one that...can offer.
We're also going to offer...this is will show you some really cool features
...cross-platform space which allow you to
...reuse your cross-platform code.
And, also allow us
allow you guys to user state of the art coding features so the advance features encoding,
for example, refactoring and cross-platform intelligence it doesn't
end there will also take the same experience you guys are used today on the
windows platform and extend that from the anger platform working at bing maps and
office and internal partners over a period of time we believe we have the fastest android
...other today on the platform.
And, to top this all...we essentially, you know,
really believe in you guys having a very fast...and debug cycle so for the
error platform specifically we're also...the microsoft x eighty-six
...emulator...based on library it's fast.
It's super cool so all this is available now envisions
...twenty-fifth in rc it will also be available community addition.
At this point I would actually look for any questions you guys might...so far before actually
going to demos does anybody have any questions so far.
You...all happy excited question sir yes sir.
How far...a...the ask experience I will answer that question in the last fifteen minutes of the presentation
...that's okay sir?
...to install on the mac on the linux system I will also see
also see that shortly domain ...me one that might be a better idea.
...that's actually go...the first...of the day so who here was actually the
...as well for cross-platform a few folks here.
So, she demo this app and we're going to actually talk about how we create this
happen so on so the apple going to show you guys's the monty potts native activity and
...application is coming from the android...kit and native activity for you guys
...not very familiar with...platform is a style of...programming
majority and almost all your coda cplus-plus you still have a very ten java
...top but that's really for show.
So, we're going to go demo that's
a for doing that I'm actually going to move back here and wake-up my machines here.
And, also change my.
Display poured here.
All right so.
If you guys want to try this out at home or if you guys really have is two-twenty fifteen
rc this is actually a sample so you can go here
you can see here that I already install this you guys can install
...well and try it out yourself.
It's pretty easy so that's...let's take a look at this project
right so here is the more teapot android project.
This has to projects within that there is a native activity project
...that for you guys.
And, then there is the packaging project.
The needed activity project here contains all the cc...code that you have for
...application and if I take a look at property pages you'll
notice that this is building a dynamic shared library for those of you guys are not very familiar with the
...reprogramming again this is...the building...the windows platform.
Using probably pages you guys can also...modify some other project characteristics,
for example, I can go ahead and choose the platform tool set
I want to choose we currently support both clang and
...and this is coming from the android...
You can actually go ahead and choosy target api level you want to use
for an application we support up to a parallel twenty-one currently working fast
on updating these...well on the latest api level.
All the other property pages...also been migrated to work with
...and dc so
...something new in our tilting remember the native actively
projects building that c cplus-plus library that cc buffers libraries then
getting used up in the packaging project which invokes the and...system.
And, takes that cplus-plus library and gives you an android into an application or
...pk file which you can then debug...
So, next I want to show you guys of the features that we have from according perspectives let's jump into
some code here so I'm going to look for this function call android main.
Which is in the more teapot native activity dot...source file?
Now android main is
...native activity function it's almost like an entry point function is
very similar to an into main function in windows thirty-two console application.
I'm actually going to go ahead and add a log message here.
Very similar to the one above.
Notice as I'm doing this the android specific
intel's is lighting up and helping me out here.
So, I'm going to say this is during the live demo.
So, we've actually done work to enable
...specific analysis which lets you not only view the api the you want to
use but also the type information and all that kind of other information...this from
...windows platform respective.
All the other features...you guys are used to, for example.
If I want to go ahead and look at the definition let's say for id I can use the
...definition window to be able to do this nicely so I can see
here that the very for this variable id...
I can also use of the other advanced refactoring features, for example.
Glanced coding features like refactoring
...twenty fifteen we also released the ability to be able to refactoring
...code now that parameter name I don't particularly like that name
bad engine bad demo doesn't some...
great so actually going to change that now so for doing this I'm going to use the refactoring feature
...to go and say we name I want to chain this...good engine great demo.
So, notice what I click preview it actually gives me the uses of this
particular type across my source file I can select or
...based upon my intuition and based upon where
this changes being made for now I'm going to click apply and hope everything works.
Now next...show you...to debugging experience so for doing so I'm going to set up a variety of
...points here.
Park box there we go there's a big points that I'm setting
and that will allow me to show you guys debugging experience so notice
the...many here dropout many is already populated with
the simulator entry this is the fast x eighty-six hyper be ways to microsoft
...emulator.
This is already running in the...let me show you guys this.
Very quickly so that's the
...running their since I already have the running next is going to have five which
will build my application and deployed to emulator.
So, there we go the applications getting built.
And, now...getting copied and install to emulator notice that the break one
...that was had.
Before we go ahead and look into the debugging experience focus let's focus on this
tool and underweight this is the...android...window
anti-lock had is a debugging and diagnostic tool that and provides
gatehousemedia view the system debug output and this can be particularly useful that I'm actually debugging
of my app when let's say...startup and it's hard to attach the mother so on so I can add
my log messages there and see what's going on so as a part of experience
we've also integrated some of the and debugging tools and diagnostic tools here right into your core editing and
debugging experience as you can see for now
...continue which allow me to show you guys the
...message lighting up here.
So, I'm going-to go ahead and continue again.
And, now let's...talking about the debugging experience here are the
...is ...or essentially based on the android...layer of software
that gets provided as you can see it's very similar to any debugging
...windows code you can go ahead
...points all your regular stuff like the autos window here let me
...that the locals window all that kind of stuff lights up nicely
...stack will allow you to view the call stack was application as you can see...the android
main function...we currently only support debugging cplus-plus code today.
You can also go to break points window can see the different break points that you guys have said here
...different source lines that I have.
And,...this is not enough and you see...you know,
users who...using this from command-line perspective you can also taskmaster directly to
gdp so I can go ahead and said debug gb exec and say
bt visual give-me-a-call stack.
And, as you can see that's exactly the same thing the...was...an android main so on.
So, that said I'm actually going to go ahead and
the delete my break points here.
So, I can show you the app running yes I want to be able to do that and...continue.
So, that's the app running
on the emulatorI have a touch-screen luckily so I can do stuff like this.
And, as I mentioned the microsoft...emulator provides in addition to being fasten based
on x eighty-six...also provides me inability of
...of sensors that I can use so not only can actually play around from
attach perspective I can also play from...perspective...
on the multi touch mode and then I can do something like...to zoom or I can shun the...together.
Let's do this we go and if I if I
want to bring them back will actually come back as...finishes.
I can also do other things here...
... I can also do other things here, for example,
I can go ahead and change the rotation that I
have from application I can change rotation for the emulator itself.
And, then figure out how map looks like in different ...as user actually, you know,
prefers user vertical orientation versus the horizontal orientation that's not going
...relaunch this.
It's actually really fast the loop here for being able to
deploying debug you can see here now like I can actually play the layouts here.
But,...experienced just doesn't
end there the annan emulator also provides you with another part of
sensors a you guys can use for testing your application under great
similar environments which are hard to reproducing...world so, for example,
when I bring up this additional tools window you can see the kilometer sensor location
sensor that we provide so I can actually go look for space needle here?
And, you'll see that come up and you can use this information
...app so on I can simulate my app under different network speeds.
If you if you guys are be can...players ...you know, playing the last life there this
might be important so on so using these kind of techniques you can actually really
test your app in a very good...environment and make sure that works for users so on.
So, that said this actually brings me to the end of the first demo and I'm going to back go back
So, the question let me rephrase the question if I'm...right so you
add the question is that what about apps that have java code in them and what a
bad building them and being able to debug them so on so you see notice here
if and I was doing the demo I can probably go back to mine the machine here quickly?
You'll notice that we have to projects here we have the...project...the packaging project.
The packaging project essentially
...right now and has the capability to build java code?
Viet stone support you know, a language service experience for java and debugging for java
Again, is you know, something that you might take a look at based on the feedback that we get from
...so on I hope that answers your question sir thank you any...
...again, in the emulator yes I believe there's...support
their and that if you guys when...meeting at the builds we can probably work and,
talk or...that?
Viet don't have any tools for performance profiling as a part of the integrated
...experience but there are tools out there that you guys can use and top of
...tool chain you guys might now I might take just one more question there actually.
So, the question is are any of these tools going-to be automated
...the provide support for automation for testing frameworks so on
...the answers that so currently you know, so, this is essentially you're exactly
...tool chain that we provide...mean, you know,
from my perspective if you guys want to be able to use, you know, your command-line test cases frame
is build and be able to drive the indicate build or drive the build system that we have
four android here which is based...build you guys can do that but we don't have ourselves
any test tools that we integrated from a test unit testing perspective automation framework at.
So, that saidI'm going to go into my next demo and by the way here
...again.
Here are so the features that we talk about here we talk about building and
native activity the client dc tool chain refactoring intel's since the...native debug are
...and fast emulation now everything I've shown you for debugging right here you
guys can also bringing you existing or application from whatever id they're using and you
can debug that...studio...provide support for that as well if you have time will get into
that demo soif you go ahead and go to next gemini.
So, the next demo here so this is a cross-platform talk right so I
...start simple...the providing...overview what you've
...android...the next application that I'm going to show you guys this is a cross-platform
...targeting the windows and the android platform the application is
call image manipulation and what it does is that it takes the life...it takes a
...camera feed and it's able to run a variety of image
filters on it you can run image reductions
...cooler...and all that kind of stuff and the application filters that I just talked
about our cross-platform cplus-plus which makes a majority of this application?
To demo this let me actually
start which showing you guys the app itself so you guys can understand where I'm coming from.
Someone move back to my micro html here.
...one of...devices so this is not...emulator this is a third-party software
...using which allows me to screencast map so, let me show the app itself now.
So, here we go here's the app so you can see I can take I can take a
life camera feed let's take this phone, for example,
and, actually I can overlay taus on it and then I can move these...
...can also do...effects I can actually go here and now use the
more filter more filter vo works better with light here we go common.
...good so the...actually add the more fact to your
life camera feed we have also other sensors like...sensor visual...reduction so on.
And, just for...back now just...cakes we also have the
...the same application running...the windows devices well.
So, let's go there so let me show that as well as...
So, that's that operate here.
I can actually again take the...camera feeds is going to
...hard to do I can do like image reduction on it and,
...can image reduction on it so on and rescinded back to rgb so I
can do the exact same stuff that I was doing online or application is the point so
...said let's take a look at how this applications architected
as...doing that I will demo some of our cross-platform features so
...done with the solution someone open my next...makes solution so we're currently
working on making this sample available as well for you guys you guys can go ahead and online
and download this...currently not available online.
So, let's take a look here as I
mentioned the image manipulation app is a cross-platform cplus-plus application
...targets the android and the windows platform if you take a look.
At the library in the image...library folder here you see
to projects you'll see the image filters android project and you'll see the image
filters windows project both these projects essentially,
for example, the image filters android project.
Reference the image filters dot shared component and
this shared component essentially which is right here.
Is all the cross-platform cplus-plus codes all this code here is cross-platform
cplus-plus and it's getting reference both in the android project...in this project?
Let's actually go ahead and build...now so you guys can see what happens enable this the mean
...remove my...file here.
And, let's go and build the.
Let's go and build a...project.
...we...already built.
So, notice as...building it will actually start the building all the cross-platform code here so if
you take a look here and compare this to this output this is actually pretty much the same
seatbelts the shared code.
And, it also those the when android specific piece of code
...all the shared code right here, for example,
the filters out to...histogram cp and then...the android specific
code component and produces us dot a file or static library.
If I now go ahead and build the windows project which also
references the shared component here you guys are going to see exactly the same thing as well it
will also build the shared code here using a different compiler
...using the vc compiler now all the shared code here.
And, it will also then build the windows specific piece of code which is actually right here in
the windows project itself this is also building static
library these static libraries are then used in these projects here, for example,
dynamic...packaging project and the image manipulation windows set of projects here to
building end-to-end android and windows application.
So, using this kind of approach you can actually share your cross-platform cplus-plus
...using this kind of a project structure also if you
notice this solution has to projects android and windows as building and...windows
that I can actually go ahead right click on the solution and build for windows
an android simultaneously.
This will take some time so at this point I...look for some questions you have any questions and how the sharing
...stuff works?
Yeah, I will...all the...files and all that kind of stuff that so the question is actually between
...files and stuff like that you.
No, it's not...linux yet I would say not
known ever but not yet...here's a question the...as well.
Right so how you handle independent dealers so if you notice you know,
there is the...project itself and the windows project here you can actually go ahead
right click here called the property pages and you can actually go let's say
in your librarian here in this case is a static library so maybe not there.
But, I can go ahead and my native activity project which is actually referencing the static lab that we just
...go in the link or providers inputs whatever my lab dependencies
are and I can do exactly the same thing in the windows project as well and, you know,
reference my components the share progress structures there for one purpose for sharing that cross-platform
...cplus-plus code and that's pretty much it is almost like a folder we build that
...twice using different compilers feynman...the thing is that
you don't have to tvs you-can from one-click builds the solution and you get
to projects here...applications...one for windows and one for android and...can extend this
files as well if you like...crash so take a look here here's my image manipulation
...that garbled which is the windows application
and here I have the image manipulation android on a became which is my android into an application.
Does anybody finds cool you think this is good?
All right so the next thing I'm sure you guys
then is I'm actually going to go ahead and add a new filter here in measured
code the beauty of cplus-plus obviously is that now that actually?
Have all this cross-platform ness available to me adding new
features easy because I only have to add them once so I'm going to go back to
And, copy that into here also while you guys
...looking I'm going to make some other edits.
And, go back to my...added.
...back to filter's.
Go back to find features.
Right here notice
has added this code you will see multi-color squiggles lighting up
different colors...is read this is purple so on and color-blind so-and-so
...level by us mood...anybody in the room know what these different kind of
...google's...
...take a guess.
And, purple is good that's good no it's you close.
As anybody else in one...this.
So, the multi-cores google sega is a seeing a light up here is because what I've just
...that I've taken ish I've ever open up my shared source file is
filters on cp...added code there
that is not platform agnostic is platform dependent if I
hope over the squiggles you'll notice that when I...the enrich google you'll notice here this is a windows
...explains lining up and it's telling me that this api message that of added
is actually specific to the...to the...platform and the windows intel's actually doesn't
...this likewise if I homer over the mone twenty-eight intrinsic types this
...language extension the microsoft provides an over here this is the
...experience lighting up and telling me that I don't know what to do this is definitely
...so using this experience from cross-platform
intelligence perspective...you working or shared layer of code we will be able to save
you time by telling a design-time the code that you've added is not going to
build...is going to build or not...for all your platforms.
And, this is actually not even compiling your code.
Also something else I should mention here is that if you look at the allocation of this feature
...detector which is open cv type you'll notice that there is
...their squiggles appearing here to both for the and platform and the
wing of platform that's because I'm actually using different versions of the open
...library for these...for the windows platform and the from the...for the...platform so at
this point either have a choice to go ahead and use a different kind of feature detector.
Or I can actually go ahead and
...my code given the lazy programmer that I am.
I'm going to if my code.
So, here's my if that's coming back to life.
Notice as the if...take
effect at that currently you'll see the android section of code is fades away
and that's because currently we have chosen the windows specific context for intelligence.
If I go ahead and choose now the android specific context
...or...language services...android portion of code is
now highlighted and the windows portion fades away so this is essentially one of our value
...server offering many working in that share layer of code to be able to use
features like this to help you guys when...when you're developing that cross-platform layer of super-fast...
So, for now I'm actually going to go ahead and
build this app I was a nice enough to tell you guys what...does.
And,...what this new filter does?
This filter that I just added what it does is that it takes life camera
feed and find interesting feature points, for example,...and edges so
on this is kind of like the stuff that you do with real-time computer vision for being able to
track object movement and that kind of stuff so let's go ahead and show you guys
the app itself so for doing so I'm going-to go ahead
set my startup project as the packaging project which is my...projects.
As you see the devices actually change here points to my lg nexis
five device I'm going to hit a five here which is going to build map again.
And, deploy to medios.
...security stuff that we need to run.
So, you can see now that the application is being built and gets
applied to my device I will bring up my third-party
...screencast here again which is going to be friendly
...hope again we go so that's the app again and now you can see
whoops.
...go back to the app.
Have really...fingers anyways?
Here we go.
...that didn't look right...give me a second let me kill this app
...deploy it ...five again.
We...we go and notice how...you guys can see
Notice have when I'm actually doing this and using the feature find objects.
It goes ahead and who doesn't seem to be able to...up right now?
Whoops.
We'll...if you see here is actually
...up nicely even having the camera close this need to focus notice
...actually getting all my source code and lighting up all the edges and the
corners and the text if I do in the key bode.
It works better lighting you'll notice that it's picking up all the texan
...keys so on so you guys can see, you know,
lifers eleven developed here now how we do...time so within
...time great so I can so when I'm actually build
...app now and this new filter I also have...working...for the windows platform as well so
I can then use the exact same application and on the same find features filter and be
able to run and use the same feature added because I was working
that cross-platform surpasses there again so that's the end of the second
...so I'm going to go back to my slider?
Remember weapons later so you guys sign this one so,
these capabilities how...cross-platform mobile app how easily...code between platforms
...of the cross-platform and productively features like cross-platform intelligence
and talk about naturally snatches other visual link debugging aid that we provide to
our users you guys can take a look at this is really useful...debugging st l types you know,
if you have an...big instill data structure you have to go
...one my one st naps is actually visualize that information for you so you don't have to do that.
And, we also showed here in this demo how to build simultaneously multiple platforms so I believe mandel
read this demo where she showed how to build how to use bringing you existing and
...and then debugged using visual studio so I'm going to skip that but if you look at the
slides there's all the nodes...so you guys can do that...
The you can also...talks about it.
Now so something else that I want to sharedyou know,
when you guys today is basically a new announcement every making the visual see...twenty fifteen
other folks in the back room somewhere there asking questions about ios earlier starting with the
twenty fifteen rc build developers will also be able to leverage
...tool chain in visual cplus-plus to target and build ios
minors
...applications that you can debug and deploys your device to the simulator so on?
You'll be able to not only build...application but you also be able to edit them debug
them...about editing here you can use all the features that I just showed you...cross-platform
...perspective from refactoring perspective so on also will
...the same cross-platform...features and edges download
...of sharing your code easily across these platforms so that said I'm
going-to go ahead on the last one that I have for you guys today which is building
and ios application now what I do with this one so this application here that
I will show you guys now is an open gl eds application it's got this
...sharing open geo code between an annual application and, I was application?
So, let's go ahead and show you
guys that now so in the meantime you guys have any questions.
Regarding yes sir.
...I couldn't hear your lesser.
Yes, you can actually do that so if you if you if you take a look at the
and you'll see that again this demo essentially the question is how do I associate certain
bill files to be associated one platform is that
correct so the way the way this structure for sharing code works is that you
...an android specific project let's say a windows specific project again
then you have a shared component the shared component include all your shared code the android specific component
project...include you android specific code so that's how you differentiate between the
android specific sources and the shared sources there I hope that answer your question sir.
I'm going to go back here so here is my...the you guys can see I'm
using parallels here so let me just bring back from a.
Video.
So, I'm running automatic currently and I'm running
...on my windows vm so this solution that I'm showing you guys
night now is essentially the following experience if you go...filing project.
This is this template right here nothing fancy about this and what this template is
building is essentially a cross-platform application targeting android and ios?
So, if you take a look here again in this project structure now you'll
notice in the libraries folder you have android native activity project which is
...which references the open geo cross-platform app dot shared component which is right
here since referencing this source failure and this project as I
showed you earlier is building a dynamic share library already ll for the and platform?
The other project here that I'm demo ing which is also
parallel libraries project here is the open geo
...cross-platform app not ios abstract static library project?
This project here is building and ios specific library.
Its and io static libm in this case it also references that cross-platform code which is open right here.
So, for our experience ...legal reasons mostly you still need
...require...running in the background which basically
...build host and that's where all the action happens but you can as you can see you can
actually code debug build everything inside of visual studio we take care of
...that and we taker bringing their messages back so on.
Now let me-let me show you guys some of the source code here so for doing so I'm going to bring up go back to
my image filter sure ...computer.
I'm going to go back to my open gl cross-platform
...not shared component and...bring up...gutsy.
also I'm going to make sure that I choose the static library.
Or the iosspecific intel's experience here.
As high go to my...method in this case you'll notice that we've actually done the
work to bring up the intel's...for ios as well.
All the other language features that you guys are used to on the windows
platform and now hopefully in the...platform...well work here...well, for example,
I can go ahead and say showman definition of this particular type and...definition work for you.
So, that's some of our language...feature all other features like refactoring and all that
...works here as well so let's now go ahead and build this ios app
rate so for doing so I essentially have.
Going to move out of...
Wing of rugby...to move out of the shared space here and.
Chugai something else now so as soon as you guys can see that.
All right so here I'm going to start up my.
...remote which is essentially a node...which listens for requests from and visuals to instance.
I'm not going to go back to...my visual studio and I'm going-to go ahead
and say that please build me my ios application.
Asses app is getting...you'll notice the output window leaving this back.
You'll see in the output...that this is actually building
mayo stuff here for me so in this case both the projects that we had which is
the ios application project and the as static library project...
Thanks I will show you
...debugging experience so for doing so I'm going to several break point here and I'm going to hit fife.
Getting aiff will try to deploy them the application the ios application on my
device which is right here you can see screencast that right here
notice that the application at this...deployed and if I go
back to my demo here.
Let's continue with that sorry let's try this again.
Less concurrent apply...application again.
Go back to my screen.
And, let's go back to bs now again sorry.
And, you'll notice that...break point as...was actually hit.
So, as you guys can see not only can we build...applications we can actually
...them using visual studio since because this is the first it's actually
the firstoccurrence of the break...getting hit in the cubed...function when
actually hit continue this is the first-time the shape online device will be rendered.
When keeping continue here...those threads again sorry?
The screencast...actually working...the
...expenses working so what's happening here when we're actually building this application is
that in secret we're doing is that we're taking the vc express project which is the
...static library project and the as application project and we produce
...project out of it then we take that
...project and...pass that over to our remote the...tool that's running on the
...which is relation running on the...it takes...called project bills it produces
the ipa file and then you can take that ipa file and...can deploy to a device or
similar you can do all this stuff from bs...you can build so on.
Right so that's...so I'm glad you brought that up so let me go back here
what building the way so currently the bits...offering for
...experience are this is kind of like our current thinking at this point so,
you'll see that we have a good story for cplus-plus of as
far as the has the story for building...storyboards objective...
concerned we don't have a great story there yet but we allow you to basically building
objective see coherent bs as well...don't have like storybook integration stuff like that so
you'll notice you'll notice here in this particular case that this is the cross-platform I
was application project and it references the static library so this project
right here takes to static library that was being built by the I
was static library project and once...consumes that actually
...the objective sequel which is right here in the app delegate dot m and the game and
...you controlled out so on also you'll find here the main story
...is here in this template so what we're really doing here is that we've already creeds project
...particular case but if you have like a really heavy cc
...application then you probably have very little, you know,
you have a ui container...open...surface perhaps and then
the textiles component there so you guys can use...transfer now...again these are preview
bets over the...will be working on preparing a story which is
more robust and a complete story for ios but this is...line of thinking
we still want you guys try this out and give us feedback because I will help us so I'm going to go and try
...experience again one more time because I can show that properly in the meantime
you guys have questions please keep them coming now so we're almost at the end of this so...
Right so the question is if I want to be able to run this on a
...server like build a my server.
Right so the I think I think it's definitely possible I'm not sure like if it's legally
possible I think some of the ios euler's don't allow us to be able to do that
scenario but I could be wrong there but definitely I mean I don't have the answer from a perspective of like how much
time do you need but as you can see that
if I go ahead and build this code again you'll notice that it's actually really,
really fast what I'm going to do this time is that since my screencast so notice actually hit
debug...I...to show you...debugging experience again so,
let me just try to minimize this parallels window and
make sure my screencast is running correctly so?
...I can either currently work on a parallels
...or the other that sense so machines now
...I'm good...the other questions you guys have.
Someone sir.
Right so yes, you can't do debugging yet but you can currently, currently
as the...rc you can actually open up your jar source files and, them
as text files but that is something that, you know, we're thinking about very
...we haven't yet made them into the byproduct bits that but that's something that, you know,
...change in the upcoming releases are there are no question sorcery sr.
So, the question is there a plan for the us editor for the...platform...you know,
I think I think from a priority prospectively might look at java first and then a ui but,
I mean I...say no here I mean a year-ago you know, we wouldn't even dream to have triangle of...tool to
...a running inside visual studio in parallel the decrying without
...own compiler until sets?
This currently only...for ios the question is
...this actually enablement work only for ios or does it work from mac os
...so on it currently only...are preview bits again and we
currently only support the developing for the ios platform?
Right so the question is...we
...api is...you guys can essentially use the as a platform...there is
...the question so, yeah, so,
currently in our story like how many...national examine your below
...actually is a very popular solution these days
...providing a platforms bachelor and csharp right we are approach is
...different...we provide is the ability since...apple's is actually...all these platforms
...the ability to target and use that tool chain but we don't necessarily
...the ability to be able to.
You know, to be able to use a platform...there so,
that's basically so we target the we use the clang and dk tool
chain that android provides of...tools...provides the use the x code
...and the and the...tool chain the apple kind...compiler that they provide and
their set of api and that's basically our story for now so now the questions I
...verse hands here.
Yes, sir.
Right so the question is can actually use the stuff that I
demos to build the...plug-ins.
The answer is that we currently haven'tbeing able to do that
it is something that people have asked us to do but we
haven't yet been able to do that as...as a priorities a little bit different but if you guys feel so
strongly about this you seem like a very interesting...talked to some please come and talked about this.
Other questions...back somewhere there.
So, I couldn't actually.
Right so the question is that the cross-platform intelligence experience that I
was lighting up there is that actually oper bull and does that does that
actually work for even the different processor architectures like sixty-four
...eighty-six is currently this features only support...platform level
...but, it is not beyond relevant managing ability
that that's notion be possible other questions they you guys have sorry yes sir?
Right so the question is this plan come bundled digital studio absolutely so if you bring up the
visual studio installer now and you go into the optional packages if you choose
the cross-platform node you will see that there's an option there to install the android and
...and once installed the error any k
you basically install the clang of the and that comes inside the indicates...for targeting android.
Other questions in the room.
...just...quickly sugars debugging experience again sorry about that like keep switching away from this
so notice like have the break one that I said my cube draw here whowas actually had and,
I can actually, you know, it continue which will run my app as you
can see the background I can actually run my apps frame by frame here you can see that as an
hidden continue map is actually running frame by frame is basically debugging from the visual
studio...your as application I can also set other break points here
that actually get hit here we go.
All the experiences that you guys are used today on the windows experience from debugging perspective
...debugging locals autos of watch
...window all of those things are supported in this particular case I have the rotation of
variable here associated my watch window and notice that actually,
you know, what between different passes as we go through the...in the cube draw
...function here also the other windows I call stack break points all that kind
of stuff that you guys today used to doing in the windows experience from a devoting perspective is actually a
available for ios as well so we would love to hear feedback from you guys and ios and the
...have to provide here?
Without said I just have a few more slides and us keep
questions coming so I know there's other people in the room that we're asking question-answer.
There is currently not support for working...existing project...this is kind of like
our preview bits you know, we've been working on this on this very hard you imagine building up
remote intel's in imagine building and more buildings and all that but now that we've got that going
...able to launch this for you guys and...works so as you guys can see those kind of
scenarios are absolutely a priority scenarios for us...question the back-room sorry.
We...on yasser so you can actually you can actually look at
our property pages we allow you to choose neon instructions are different
...vx instructional into hardware so on so you guys can just, you know,
change properties and property page and be able to levers those features so I'm almost out of time
here I just want to mention that there's ...also have...integration...examine amanda
in our talk about this you can read my blog there so now when you're actually working
...including...code you don't have to go to other id to do that you can actually do all
the visual studio you can also debug these...android native code that
...the cc pasco the writing...being reference from is...project you
can debug that visual studio as well so we've...them in order to do that you can read my blog for more
details there you can follow us on the visual studio dot com page and...blog which is
...blog that the fob see we talk about other new features their the visual
...dot com page there is about all up...what this product provides from a functionality
...feature perspective as new features...those things will be updated and
...the last slide here that I have which is
what evaluations so please help us here to understand how we can do better in
presenting the material that we have for you guys have the speakers to be able...prepared the
next time if you guys have feedback so please go ahead and let us know
how we can learn improve so that's sad that's all material that I had to present I
will be offline off-stage here and you guys can ask...questions you guys want thank you.